Russian Painting Photograph Collection
Yale University Arts Library
Russian Painting Photograph Collection
1900-2005
VRC 57
Yale University Arts Library
3.75
9 boxes
Collection of mounted black and white and color reproductions of Russian paintings. Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Collection of mounted black and white and color reproductions of Russian paintings. Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders.
Arrangement
Organized by individual artist name. The individual artist material is further divided primarily by location of work. The individual art portion is preceded by an Anonymous grouping arranged chronologically.
Painting, Russian; Photographs; Reproductions
- General Unknown Artists (Box 1)
  General
  [5 photographs]
  Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings
  - 12th century [5 photographs] (Box 1)
  - 13th century [ 2 photographs] (Box 1)
  - 14th century [12 photographs] (Box 1)
  - 15th century [15 photographs] (Box 1)
    - Novgorod School. 10 photographs (Box 1)
  - 16th century [23 photographs] (Box 1)
  - 17th century [8 photographs] (Box 2)
  - 20th century [1 photograph] (Box 2)
    Includes six folders of miscellaneous clippings
- Known Artists: A-Z (Box 2)
  - A-F: [20 photographs] (Box 2)
  - G-M [22 photographs] (Box 2)
  - N-Z [43 photographs] (Box 2)
  - Aivazovsky, Ivan Konstantinovich [3 photographs] (Box 3)
  - Archipenko, Alexander [5 photographs] (Box 3)
  - Bakst, Leon [25 photographs] (Box 3)
  - Bashkirtseff, Marie [3 photographs] (Box 3)
  - Brullov, Karl Paulovich [2 photographs] (Box 3)
  - Burliuk, David [9 photographs] (Box 3)
  - Chagall, Mark [27 photographs] (Box 3–4)
    - 1910-1919 (26 photographs) (Box 4)
    - 1920-1929 (12 photographs) (Box 4)
    - 1930-1939 (10 photographs) (Box 4)
    - 1940-1949 (25 photographs) (Box 4)
    - 1950-1959 (16 photographs) (Box 5)
    - 1960's, 1970's, 1980's (18 photographs) (Box 5)
  - Deineka, Alexander [3 photographs] (Box 5)
  - Delauny-Terk, Sonia [7 photographs] (Box 5)
  - Gabo, Naum [2 photographs] (Box 5)
  - Gerasimov, A.M. [1 photograph] (Box 5)
  - Gherassimoff, Serguey V. [2 photographs] (Box 5)
  - Goncharova, Natalia [11 photographs] (Box 5)
  - Grigorieff, Boris [9 photographs] (Box 5)
  - Jawlensky (Box 5)
    Xx Germany
  - Kandinsky, Wassily (Box 6)
    - 1903-1908 (16 photographs) (Box 6)
    - 1910 (12 photographs) (Box 6)
    - 1911-1912 (20 photographs) (Box 6)
    - 1913 (15 photographs) (Box 6)
    - 1914-1919 (17 photographs) (Box 6)
    - 1920-1924 (22 photographs) (Box 7)
    - 1925-1929 (18 photographs) (Box 7)
    - 1930's (24 photographs) (Box 7)
    - 1940's (8 photographs) (Box 7)
  - Korovine, KA. [1 photograph] (Box 7)
  - Kutateladze, Appolon K. [2 photographs] (Box 7)
  - Lorionov, Mikhail [5 photographs] (Box 7)
  - Levitan, Isaak [4 photographs] (Box 7)
  - Lissitzky [11 photographs] (Box 8)
  - Malevich, Kasimiv [23 photographs] (Box 8)
  - Meninsky, Bernard [3 photographs] (Box 8)
  - Popova, Liubov [7 photographs] (Box 8)
  - Repin, Ilya Jefimovich [8 photographs] (Box 8)
  - Rodchenko, Alexandre [11 photographs] (Box 8)
  - Rublov, Andrey [8 photographs] (Box 8)
  - Serov, Valentin A [7 photographs] (Box 8)
  - Soudeikne, Sergei [1 photograph] (Box 8)
  - Tchelitchew, Patel (Box 9)
    - Drawings [28 photographs] (Box 9)
    - Paintings [13 photographs] (Box 9)
  - Vasilieff, Nicholas [2 photographs] (Box 9)
  - Vasiliev, V. [1 photograph] (Box 9)
  - Vereshchagin [1 photograph] (Box 9)